Okay.
>> Okay.
And so we are admitting everybody from
the lobby. Good morning everyone. My
name is uh Dominic Zerlo and I am with
the New Mexico Department of Health. And
uh we're uh getting ready to start the
meeting. We're just admitting everyone
from the lobby. That does sometimes take
a minute or so. So, um, we'll just, uh,
while while we're waiting for everyone
to join on in, um, just a few items to
remember is this meeting is recorded. We
do put it online after the meeting is
over. Does take a few business days for
that to occur. Um, so we do ask that
people remember to keep language
appropriate. Um, and then the other item
that we have been asked sometimes is why
we do not have visual on for everyone.
And the we only keep that with a couple
of people including the chair simply
because uh there are some areas where we
still do not have the greatest internet
connection and broadband support um in
the state. And so we want to ensure
people can stay on as much as they can.
And if we have a lot of people on
camera, that takes up a lot of the
bandwidth and they tend to uh end up
dropping off more often than what
happens already sometimes. And so that
is part of the reason we do that. Um and
um with that I'd like to turn it on over
to Dan Jennings who is the chair of this
committee. And so Dan, the meeting is
yours.
>> Good morning. Thank you very much. Uh
Don, appreciate you doing the
introductions on everything. And I
really glad to have everybody here for
our next uh RACI
meeting. Uh just a couple of reminders
about what our purpose is of course is
that this on our slide screen here is
what we're here for. uh our couple of
recommendations and responsibilities
recommend guidelines for research and
data collection. Uh these are going to
be things like the core data elements,
outcome monitoring, um ethical research
practices, evaluation frameworks and
such. So that's what we've been working
on for the last couple of meetings. I'm
glad that y'all are here again with me
this Friday. Just a couple of things
that we'll do is we'll start off like we
normally do with some introductions. And
while we would love for everybody to
introduce themselves, I'd love for you
all to be able to get in the queue. And
while we're doing that, I'd like for our
team at Department of Health to kind of
introduce uh themselves and also give
any kind of updates during this time as
to what the other uh the board's been
doing and some upcoming information that
might be helpful. So again, for
everybody that wants to provide their uh
introductions to this, uh please do so
by raising your hands and you'll be able
to raise your hands by clicking on the
raise hand button there. And then
whenever you'll be unmuted, just know
that you can turn your mic on at that
time. So during this time, go ahead and
raise your hand to be ready and then
I'll bring the DO team up.
>> Thank you, Dan. Um and I'll actually
wait if it's okay with you, Dan. We'll
do the um uh the updates after all the
introductions.
>> Um and uh so so as I mentioned when the
we first started online, my name is
Dominic Zerlo and I'm the center
director for medical cannabis and
psilocybin. Um and so Jorge, would you
announce yourself?
>> Hello. Good morning everyone. My name is
Jorge Gonzalez. Uh I am the uh medical
psilocybin program manager.
>> Thank you Jorge Braymond.
Good morning everybody. Raymond Gigos.
I'm the systems and data analyst for uh
cannabis and psilocybin.
>> Thank you Raymond. Brenda.
>> Good morning and happy Friday everyone.
I'm Brenda Martinez. I'm the deputy
director for the center for medical
cannabis and psilocybin.
>> Thank you Brenda. Carmen.
>> Hello everybody. My name is Carmen
Batista. I'm a health educator with the
program.
>> Thank you. K Rob.
>> Good morning everybody. I'm Robert
Shrekner. I'm the medical director for
both the psilocybin and medical cannabis
programs. Pleasure to be here.
Thank you Rob. Ishmael.
>> Hello everybody. My name is Ismail
Zutad. I'm one of the health educators
here at the program.
>> Thank you Ishmael. Johnny,
>> good morning everyone. My name is Johnny
Musher. I am a management analyst here
with the program.
>> Thank you, Johnny. Kathy,
>> morning everyone. I'm Kathy Aljier, IT
project manager.
>> Great. Thank you, Kathy. All right, Dan,
those are all the individuals. So,
>> appreciate it. Thank you all very much.
And uh now it's time for everybody else
on the call to be able to be in the
queue for introductions. And again, we'd
love for your introductions. We'll kind
of keep them of course short, but please
from let us all know who you are, where
you're coming in from, um if you're New
Mexico or outside of New Mexico. Uh your
affiliation, if you have any affiliation
with any organizations, and if this is
your first time being here or if you're
returning and uh just kind of fair a
little bit with the team. So, appreciate
y'all.
First here we have uh Gregory Evans.
Gregory, I have enabled your microphone.
Please unmute yourself when ready.
>> Good morning.
My name is Gregory Evans. I'm an
independent researcher and home
micologist with no affiliations.
I reside in Santa Fe. I've been here for
about six years. My intention here is to
support the program's development
through committee recommendations which
are aligned with emerging research and
beex practices. My specific focus is in
data analytics and chemical analysis of
psilocybin containing mushrooms and how
those can be applied to unique
therapies.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next we
have Danielle Leonard. Danielle, I have
enabled your microphone. Please uh yeah,
speak when ready.
>> Hi, my name is Danielle Leonard. Um it's
my first time sitting in on this
committee which I'm very happy about and
glad to meet you all. Um I'm a therapist
in Santa Fe and I'm also a researcher at
New Mexico Highlands University. Um my
field is in um peak and mystical
experiences.
I uh study this across diverse uh
contexts including psychedelics,
psychedelic therapy um but also everyday
moments in uh nature, art, music and all
the many forms that peak experiences um
arise. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next we
have Dan Houston. Dan, I've enabled your
microphone. Please unmute yourself when
ready.
>> All right. uh Daniel Houston, Rose City
Laboratories, the psilocybin lab in in
Portland, Oregon. Um glad to be a part
of some of these meetings and just uh
want to help the system progress
forward.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next, we
have Harvey King. Harvey, I've enabled
your microphone. Please unmute yourself
when ready.
Just as a reminder for anyone who wants
to unmute themselves and have their mics
enabled, the microphone uh icon is on
the top right hand side. Um little
microphone sign there. Just click on
that. If you're having any trouble
there, it's often uh the case that one
may have to drop off the call and join
back in. However, if you join back in,
just pop your hand back up and we can
enable your microphone at once. Um,
we'll be moving on to James Brown.
James, um, I have enabled your
microphone. Please begin when ready.
>> Thank you, sir. And morning, Dan, and
everybody else in this group. Again, my
name is James Brown. I'm a doctor of
pharmacy here in New Mexico. Um, I love
my New Mexico. I love my New Mexicans.
That's why I'm here to represent. Um, I
do represent a new organization called
Five Degrees North Healing Foundation.
We are nonprofit. um looking to be a s a
center uh to provide services to people.
Um my background is in pharmaccoinetics
uh dynamics uh research. Um everybody I
I I love policy. I love uh safety. Um I
I'm here for multiple meetings and I'm
glad to return this morning on this
great Friday and to be with all of you
again. Thank you so much and it's a
pleasure.
Thank you very much for that. Next we
have Kate Hawk. Kate, I have enabled
your microphone. Please unmute yourself
when ready.
>> Good morning everyone. I'm Kate Hawk in
Santa Fe. My trauma therapist uh
ketamine assisted therapy particularly
interested in end of life care. Uh and
I'd also like to see research on
psilocybin and addiction especially uh
smoking sessation. Thanks.
>> Thank you very much for that. Uh, next
we have Brenda Burgard. Brenda, I have
enabled your microphone. Please unmute
yourself when ready.
>> Hello everyone. My name is Brenda
Burgard. I am an LPCC and I'm on the
advisory board for training and
education for the medical psilocybin
program here in New Mexico. Thank you
everyone for joining us today. I really
appreciate all of you and your input and
uh let's see what this meeting has to
offer today. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much for that. And
finally, um Harvey, we have enabled your
microphone. Uh if you try to unmute
yourself, maybe uh we might have a
success. Yes, I see you unmuted there.
All right, go ahead.
>> I'm Harvey King. I live up in Talis, New
Mexico. I'm a hospice nurse and just
interested in finding out more about all
of this. First time here in the meeting.
>> Fantastic. Thank you very much, Dan.
That concludes all the uh individuals
with their hands up. I pass the floor
back to you.
>> I appreciate it. Thank you very much.
And if you weren't able to do any
introduction, you haven't done so yet,
feel free, drop it in the chat, raise
your hand at any time and we'll make
sure that you get your voice heard on
this call as well. So, uh, I'd love for,
um, I'm going to leave this slide up
here so everybody knows where to send
any information to and the program
website and where updates can come from,
but I'll let Dominic kind of let us know
a little bit more about some updates
from the rest of the other teams and the
board and especially if you were not
able to get onto some of those other
ones or see them yet. Just let's get
some updates from the team.
>> Thank you, Dan. Um, and for those who
weren't able to attend the uh advisory
board meeting last Friday, the advisory
board meeting has approved and
recommended to the secretary of health
um an outline with regard to both
testing and cultivation for psilocybin.
And so what's happening right now is uh
as a department we are taking that
outline and we are turning it into the
legal language that needs to occur for
regulations and working with state
record and archive who are the ones who
do the final draft and version of that.
And then our plan is we will be meeting
with the secretary in the next week or
so in order to be able to get
finalization of that. Once that occurs
then that recom or those regulations
will be published um and they will be
published for 30 days at a minimum. So
they'll be published for 30 days and at
the end of that 30 days we then have a
public hearing. So, what I will
recommend, and we'll be posting this to
the website as well, uh, once we publish
the, um, the rules, and so I recommend
that people look them on over, see what
mistakes we've made, see where we've
missed potential items. Um, but also
remember that these are not the final
regulations that are going to encompass
the entire program. For example, there
are still the regulations with regard to
uh providers as far as what lensures are
going to be um uh going to be eligible
and the requirements for that, the
education and the training that they
need, the locations where psilocybin
treatments will be occurring. So all of
those regulations are not yet created.
That's part of the various committees
that are meeting over the next several
months in order to be able to help
develop them just like we have done now
with the cultivation and with regard to
testing. We also know because this is
still the beginning stages that there
will be other revisions that occur to
the regulations down the road. So if
there are for example something that we
completely missed um we can still add
that on in uh down at a later point in
time um prior to the program starting in
December. And when I say program
starting I'm talking about the first
patients being seen. So please remember
that um as we're doing it but please
also go through it. We are human. Um
there's always that one item that
somebody down the road goes wait a
minute. did anybody think of? And we
need to remember to then add that on in
whether it be at this time or in a
future rule process. So, just to let
everybody know that should be coming up
over the next couple of weeks. So,
definitely check out our website uh for
that update and as soon as we have it,
we'll also be announcing it in whichever
committee meetings are occurring at that
time because this is a big step for the
program. And so, uh, really thanks to
everybody and especially the folks on
the propagation committee and who've
been involved in that, um, and Chris
Pescus who's been chairing that
committee. They just have really gone
above and beyond in helping us to get
things to the point we are and we're
really looking forward to these next
steps. So, anyway, so we have that. In
addition to that, um, just to let
everybody know is we do have a new
member of our team. Um, and her name is
Leslie Peterson and she is our senior
compliance officer. Uh, she just started
this past Monday. She's not here with us
today because she is going through the
Department of Health new employee
orientation. Um, but you will see her on
some of the future committee meetings
and board meetings. And so when you do,
please welcome her. and in in her
absence, I definitely want to welcome
her to the team and uh look forward to
working with her more and I know she's
very excited as well in the
conversations we've had over the last
week or so. Um and I think those are the
major items that we have right now. Oh,
uh sorry, I almost forgot. It's an
important one, but we um we often don't
announce it until signatures happen with
regard to funding bills, but we did have
the if you have not heard during the
legislative session, um Senator
Steinborn really went out and advocated
for the program and especially for the
equity fund and uh he was able to uh
help and secure $630,000
to go into the equity fund and then an
additional $300,000
that uh will go towards research. And so
that was actually not just Senator
Steinborn, but many other of our
senators and representatives who had
contributed to that. And so just my
thanks and the department's thanks to
them. That's also going to help the
program and especially with regard to
research here over the next couple of
years. Now, the reason I say that we
don't usually announce this is because
we are still waiting for the governor's
signature and the governor does have
until March 11th for that signature. So,
we just haven't seen that quite yet. Um,
but when that is, that will also of
course be published in public. And so,
when you see that the governor has uh
has signed the budget, so you can take a
look at that. They do include all of
that on the New Mexico legislative
website. And so, people are welcome to
go there and take a look at that. Um,
and I think that's all I have now, Dan.
So, I'll turn it on back to you.
>> Perfect. No, I appreciate the updates.
Uh, and it's really great to get some of
these uh information out because again
for some of you that this might be your
first meeting or your first introduction
to some of this stuff. So, really
appreciate getting that out. And if
you've heard it before, then sorry about
that. But I'm glad that everybody got
informed on it, which is exactly what we
need for everybody to know kind of
what's happening. So, um, and just a
reminder that if you do register for,
uh, these, uh, kind of subcommittee
meetings, if there's any kind of, um,
handouts or anything that we're going to
be having, we usually will provide that
ahead of time. So, if you register for
these meetings ahead of time, usually
about a week or so ahead of time, and
you get those in your email as well. So,
I know that some of you might be coming
in a little bit late, but the slides and
the information that we have here online
today will also be posted on the website
later. But if some of you did get it
ahead of time, then you do know what
we're kind of looking at today. So, the
next thing that we'll kind of go over is
just any changes that we've made from
the previous meeting uh that we've had.
And before we had focused on the
research and reference material so that
kind of we ground our information here
and like I said if you did receive this
ahead of time you received the links uh
these are the ones that I presented
probably this is the third time now so
I'm just going to quickly kind of hit
that so if you do have that in your
possession I hope you did get a chance
to look at it and if you haven't of
course it's posted on u the medical
psilocybin website uh so these
informations if there is any other
research arch or information that would
help the other committees or our
committee then please make sure that you
do share it with us. Uh, and if you do
so, you can use this email address. And
if you do use that email address, make
sure that you're including uh a link.
You don't need to necessarily provide
the entire uh document, but a link to it
and an explanation as to why this
information is important for the
committee uh would be great. And you can
tag it as the RACI
committee so that they'll know where it
should go. those information will be
part of minutes and then we'll bring it
up at the next meeting to discuss and to
make approvals to bring into the list.
So, just wanted to kind of give
everybody a chance to I know during this
meeting sometimes it's hard to get
everything out and in. So, I just wanted
to let everybody know how to to do this
even after the fact. So, I appreciate
everybody providing help and assistance
on uh this list as well.
The next thing that we have left over
from our last meeting and this is the
time I'd like to spend a little bit of
time on is to come to at least a little
consensus building during this meeting
and it's a tentative data collection
system and we know that um here in state
we're going to need to do some data
collection for medical psilocybin
program and so we started to build uh at
least a a data structure idea again this
is not the final version uh and it will
definitely change over time but we
wanted to kind of get at least a little
consensus about what we're looking to
build in to a data system what that
might look like. Uh again, if you
received this ahead of time, then great.
You had a chance to look at it. Um and
if you didn't, this might be your first
time, so I apologize. So, what we'll do
is we'll take it like one screen at a
time. Uh and just to kind of give you
the heads up is like anything that I put
in red were the changes that we had uh
recommendations from our last meeting
that I've tried to internalize and
integrate into this. Uh and so couple of
things to note at the top. One of the
things that was brought up the last
meeting was kind of who is the
recommended audience that would be
actually entering this data or being
part of the workflow for the data so
that it's not uh an honorous process for
one person uh one clinician one
practitioner as such. So you'll see that
I've added that up in the kind of red
box at the top and also that there were
some questions about like is this data a
mandatory data field or so. So I'm just
putting a reminder on some of these that
some of these fields may be optional. Uh
meaning that at this point we haven't
made a consensus as to this is a
mandatory data field or this is an
optional kind of data collection
research type of a field. But uh just
wanted to kind of bring those up. So
giving you some time to kind of look at
that. Uh one of the things that we did
to change was instead of date of birth
to year of birth. Uh so that that way it
doesn't collect a lot of PII
information. Uh and then down below was
a diagnosed disability. Uh a yes or no
field for that and then the zip code
because also that was part of it but I
just added more clarification. Uh the
committee last time had made a comment
that that way we can identify what state
uh the patient is a resident. So it was
asked to have a state field also but
with zip code you can capture that data
without having another data field. Uh so
before we move to the next slide, I just
would like to give time to everybody in
the group to be able to let me know is
there anything at this moment, like I
said, this will change over time, but is
there anything in this moment that
anybody has any concerns, issues,
anything with with just this data
element, this page right now. And again,
if you do want to interact, please raise
your hand. Uh and if you did want to
drop it in the chat, if you didn't want
to say out loud, that's fine. But please
raise your hand and let me know and
we'll call on you for a comment.
Not seeing any comments, but I like to
have some wait time. So the next thing I
would like to say is um I would like for
the group to be able to let me know that
like I said I would like to quote freeze
this page for a moment and just say like
if everybody would give me a hand raise
to say that at this moment this part of
the data elements looks like a
recommendation that I could bring back
to the board to make a recommendation.
Not to say that we would solidify
anything, but I do want to just get your
input to say this is something on this
page we would like to be okay with. So,
if you raise your hand to say yes, we're
okay with that. We would appreciate
that.
Great. I can't thank you enough very
much for for voting on that because it's
one thing to have that uh uh little bit
of of uh help to say this is something
that we can move forward on. So thanks
for sharing that.
This is the next page that uh we had
worked on which was kind of the patient
clinical baseline and history. Uh in
this case this suggested user for entry
would be the referring clinician. uh and
the referring clinician would be the
person that would be actually making the
referral into the medical psilocybin
program for the patient. Um the data
fields that we have up here would be
primary diagnosis, those diagnosis
duration, uh any kind of treatment
history information, the baseline
severity, and then there were two things
that were brought up from our previous
committee meeting to add in meaning a
referral from meaning what type of
referring clinician was was this
individual making the reference from and
then a health assessment in some form
fashion. That way the based upon the uh
patient qualifications and uh disposal
safety and such committees uh knowing
that this patient has been medically
cleared for any kind of psilocybin
treatment. Uh and so I'm going to let uh
Danielle I know you have a comment hand
up so I just wanted to let your voice be
heard at this point.
>> Sorry I was just putting it up to agree
from before but maybe that wasn't my
role but I do not have a comment. Yes,
>> appreciate. Thank you. Yeah, sometimes
when we do the vote and the hands stay
up. So, I just wanted to make sure if
there was any kind of comment you'd like
to to make. So, I will always call on
you. And uh I know that uh James uh put
into the chat box here. So, I just
wanted to kind of uh bring this into it
as well. James, hi. Just joining. Uh
James Fia, I'm sorry. I hope I
pronounced it correctly from
ignitesergy.com. We offer a psychedelic
therapy ehr software that can produce
these specific reports. So, thank you
very much for bringing that in. Um, so
at this point, I'd like to let everybody
on the committee ask any kind of
questions, comments, or anything on this
page for this part of the data elements.
Is there anything that I've made a
mistake on or didn't bring up or or
anything that you'd like to add or
change?
And same thing on this one. I would
appreciate then if there's uh no changes
or anything at this point if I could
have the hand raise again if we would
like to say let's move forward with this
slide and we're good with this one.
Awesome. Thank you very much. I
appreciate everybody raise your hand and
again if you wanted to leave your hand
raised that's fine. not call on you for
comment, but uh if you'd like, if you've
just voted, then you can bring your
hands down again.
And Gregor Evans, I know that you've got
Perfect. So, if you wanted to bring a
comment up, then we'll unmute your mic
and share.
Uh
>> there was a comment in the chat by
Gregory. Uh and he stipulates, do you
want to include details about previous
psychedelic usage here? All
right. Um,
if I I could ask uh let's unmute u
Gregory on that and if Gregory if you
could kind of kind of share a little bit
about what your thought about what a
field like that might look like. Would
that be just a yes no field or how would
that do you feel that that would be kind
of brought in?
>> I mean I think we could get super
granular if we wanted. Depends on who's
collecting the data and what we're
planning on doing with it. I think I
think that scope is a different
conversation. But um there are
um research papers and studies around
past usage and heightened sensitivity.
Um there is a phenomenon where it's like
say somebody's taken a massive dose in
the past 10 years ago or whatever there
if that was like something that had a
very lasting effect then that person
could
tend to be more sensitive to
psychedelics or specific psychedelics
through their experience. So it might be
worth considering in a baseline what
kind of psychedelic background they
have.
>> Okay. Um then like I would like to ask
this question. Um is that would that be
something that would be entered by the
referring clinician or do you feel that
might be something entered by the
patient themselves on the previous
screen since that might be just a yes
no. And of course with psilocybin
treatment that's collected in this
database from the state we would know
previous meaning previous through the
program uh any kind of psilocybin
treatment u but with what you're talking
about this would be previous before the
the program itself. So, u just kind of
interested.
>> Yeah, I think it's definitely something
that the clinician should be con
communicating with the patient about.
Um, and so maybe we have a mandated like
yes, no, but then like an optional free
form uh descriptor because I think we
can get a lot of information and I think
people will want to share. Um, but I
don't think it's necessarily like uh
something we would want to force for
fear of incrimination or anything like
that.
>> Right. Okay. Um, so let's uh I'm going
to
see if I can add I can't do it from my
slide. Um, so for let's let's kind of
put the consensus out to everybody on
this. Uh the recommendation brought up
by Gregory is that we on this field on
this tab we introduce maybe a yes no and
with a free form as an optional um
question for the referring clinician to
add any kind of information about past
psychedelic uh treatment. But uh I would
like to like say should this be left
over for uh any kind of psychedelic
previous treatment or just psilocybin
treatment. And so I would love to hear
other people's comments and ideas on
adding a field like that. And if you'd
like to kind of share your thoughts,
just please raise your hand and we'll
bring you on to the unmute.
>> We have a hand up there by Lisa
Ginsburg. Um Lisa, I've enabled your
microphone. Please begin when ready.
>> Um just for the for the purpose of
research and collecting qual
quantitative data, I think we should
consider if we asking these questions,
how are we going to measure the inputs?
If someone says, "Oh yes, I did it
sometime somewhere." uh can we really
take that data as as a clear input? So
it's either would require more follow-up
questions when and where and especially
if psychedelics were taken in
unregulated settings. Then there's
another set of questions about the
quality potency. Were you taking
psychedelics just psychedelics or were
you mixing it with alcohol? Was it a
party setting? Was it at a clinic? Um I
think it's a great question but would
require more thought.
>> Thank you. Appreciate that uh background
on that because it's true a lot of this
cannot just be put into a vacuum. You're
exactly right. It has to have along with
it some recommendations of how those
questions are asked and and brought into
uh into this clinical setting. So true.
Any other comments for uh adding a field
such as this?
We have a question there by James Brown.
Uh, sorry, a hand raised. Sorry. Um,
James, I've enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
>> Thank you, sir. Hey, Dan. My thought on
this, you know, as a facilitator, it is
important to get a history on somebody's
past psychedelic usage, whether that's
something outside of the scope of
psilocybin
or solosin. Um, that's sometimes very
common with these people. Sometimes it's
not. Um, I think Gregor makes a great
idea and thought. I just don't know how
we can get that in there without opening
multiple other windows, right? like it's
going to if you if you click yes on that
man that could it end up being 10 more
questions like what was it how long ago
what was the set and setting I mean we'd
want to kind of know but as a
facilitator Dan I think it's important
you know myself when sitting on people
it's it's important that we understand
what their past use was so that you can
get grasp an idea you know put you in a
ballpark of what's going to go on next
but I think it's a great idea I just
don't know how we assimilate Thanks.
>> Sure.
>> Thank you. Thank you for that. And I
know in the in the chat box, thank you
um Kenna and I hope I pronounce your
name correctly on this question may be
worth running through equity committee
to discern the potential effects of the
query on brown and black clients,
patients who were at higher risk of
incrimination. Uh and it's true we uh do
want to have this as deidentified data.
So really it's just patient identifier
number and not a name or anything like
that. But it does open up a potential
and uh sometimes Pandora's box on some
of those things. Um I'm curious
I'm curious if it's not a data
collection element but a best practice
in the role of the facilitator
uh in the clinical setting for uh the
psilocybin uh therapy or through
integration. I'm just curious if it's
something like that and not necessarily
part of a data element of this, but I'd
love to hear thoughts on that.
We have a hand raised there by Lisa
Kinsburg. Um Lisa, I your mic is still
enabled, so please begin when ready.
>> Um thank you. Uh I think that's a great
question for preparation session and on
boarding questioners. Um I I still
believe if we want to collect data which
is really important we have to be really
precise and granular with that. Um and
that can be what this form can be
a starting point and then we can build
on on that. And if you have a repeated
client then we can build on that that we
already know that the person came in
in a safe setting that is controlled in
a way and then we can start adding that
data. But I don't think this question is
appropriate for this specific form.
>> Thank you. Um I I think that uh some of
the things that were brought up about uh
like right through the equity committee
and some of the things that you have
brought up there too kind of give us an
ability to say like this could be a a
great like I said idea to bring into the
practice. Um and and as we work as a
committee through this, it might be
something that we are looking to collect
data as on best on the research practice
side of things which will um give us the
ability kind of like what you brought up
Lisa to basically say how can we make
this a data element that is
researchable, queryable and such that we
can then do some data on. So, I made a
note over in my notes for that because I
think that that's uh that's something
Gregory brought up is something that
would be beneficial to know ahead of
time. Uh and and so we'll kind of work
through this and and again like Kiana
said is that yes, it would help to go
through the equity committee on
something like this as well. So, love
this. Thank you.
Um,
and Michelle, yes, best practice is for
the guy to learn the patient psychedelic
experience history and then use that
knowledge to provide the best service.
And that's why I really appreciate uh
everybody that is interested in that. I
think that Brenda's uh subcommittee uh
would be a great place to have a lot of
this through the education training and
a lot of those best practices I think
would be flowing through um that
committee for that. So, I appreciate
everybody that's interested in that to
definitely make sure you sign up and and
you attend uh Brenda's subcommittee for
it, too.
So, there's a plug for you, Brenda.
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> Oh, well, thank you, Dan. I I Yes, the
these are really um you're doing a great
job with this because you're making my
job really easy. I really have to do
much of anything but I I shouldn't say
that either but um I think this is very
comprehensive of really going through
all of this and um trying to implement
what is needed in this information. So
in training and practice and education
this is going to be really fundamental
in all of the practices that are going
to be in training. So thank you for
doing all this hard work. Dan, you're
making my making this really beautiful.
I love it.
>> Not to have a love fest on this, but uh
Brenda, I think you're having a
subcommittee meeting after this.
>> Yes.
>> So, plug it.
>> All right. Sure. Will. Thank you.
>> No, plug it now. What time?
>> Plug it now. Okay. All right. So, I
don't mean to steal the show here or
anything. I'll make this very brief uh
because I want everybody to have their
input especially in in uh Dan's meeting
here is because this is going to be
carrying over to the training and
education part and I think this is going
to be uh vital to really understanding
the nuts and bolts of how this is going
to be um in the training. Um, a lot of
there's a lot of different trainings out
there, but the basics are there, but
this is especially specific for New
Mexico because when I took a look at
most of the training um there's some
misses here and there because they a lot
of the training that is done in Oregon
and Colorado had to kind of like go back
and and redo things. We we have it we
have it going on here. So the more input
that we get from all all of you out
there, the better and we can make this
very very um specific for New Mexico. So
please come to every meeting you
possibly can and give us your input.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. And as the same thing for as
y'all's committees are coming up with
recommendations. So for example, I think
it was on the dosage committee. Um, some
of those kind of flowed into our
committee. So, I've been updating this.
So, same thing from yours to ours. Uh,
Desba brought up a good point is that
this committee is the flow in and out of
a lot of things. So, we really want to
work together and uh, yep. Thank you
very much, Dominic. There's the there's
the meeting link right there in the
chat. So, today from 1:00 to 3:00,
Bindda's uh, committee on training
education will be held and then there's
the rest of uh, the upcoming committees
there too. So for this slide, I would
love to just kind of ask if we could do
again the hand raise for the kind of
vote to say at least on this we're kind
of good at the way it is to kind of go
forward to make this recommendation to
say this is where we could kind of land
right now. So and just raise your hand
if you're good.
Thank you all very much for that. uh
we'll move on to the next one which kind
of does land itself right into the uh
session logistics uh and so this would
be really for the facilitator the
practitioner that would be working uh
with the patient at this time. So again
the suggested user for entry on this one
would be the administering clinician and
uh again there are linkages back to the
patient identifier information the date
of the session uh the facilitator's
license information number so that there
is a linkage to the facilitator um and
there was recommendation to move the
medications that the patient might be on
at the same time into the session
because this would change over time not
just a one-time fix thing. So the
facilitator would just uh do a double
check against any kind of medications
that the patient might be on at the
time. Um and then we start moving into
things like tracing to the product lot
number uh the dosage and through the
dosage committee we're working on
getting the details back on this but the
dosage of what uh psilocybin was was
provided the dosage form uh and then
last committee meeting uh we were
brought up and I think this was on
Gregory's recommendation a dosage like
mode how the dose was actually delivered
uh and administration mode was this an
individual or a group or a diad Uh, and
the setting type, was this in a clinic
or home or retreat center? Uh, we've got
another slide on this, but for the
moment, I just want to stay on this
slide and ask if there's any like
changes, anything that you wanted to
bring up. And, uh, I see Gregor's got
his hand up, too. So,
>> nope, that was just left over.
>> Perfect.
>> Sorry.
any comments or anybody have any changes
that they would like to see on this this
part of the session logistics at the
moment? Um, anything that I've missed
and not Oh, yes. Got a hand up from Dan.
>> Hey. Um
uh is is I just want to ask uh where in
here um would you be putting the potency
slash all the minor tryptoines and
everything for the dosage? Is that where
it would be?
>> So the there is another page that we've
added for medicine. So I've created a
table table for medicine which would be
the product lot number and then the COA
information would be on that. So this
way the clinician is not necessarily
having to enter in all of the details
about the actual medicine itself because
that is already in the database from the
the actual uh registered grower.
>> Awesome. Sorry, I'll wait.
>> No, no, no, no, no. It's a perfect thing
to bring up because this is exactly why
I wanted to kind of break it apart so
that it's already in another area and
that way the the session administer uh
does not have to reenter a lot of that
information
because I know there's a lot more
information to go on during a session
than just kind of keeping track of a lot
of this. So that way try to lighten that
load for the clinician the facilitator.
Um, so before I go to the next slide,
which is a little bit more about the
session, can I just get a raise of hand
that we're good with this one here so
far as it stands.
Perfect. Thank you all very much for
that.
And then here's the second slide of that
one. Again, this is uh when we talked
about this is from a research
standpoint. So again, some of these
fields may be optional, may not be a
mandatory. So I just wanted to highlight
that um this is something that we had
already introduced from the previous um
committee meeting. So this is just again
just a repeat of this. This would be for
the clinician to be able to enter in the
prep time, the time that was uh spent in
time in minutes with the patient prior
to session for preparation. Uh the time
of administration, the time of first
onset, time of peak intensity, and time
of resolution to help kind of give the
entire duration of that session.
Um and so perfect a couple of questions
coming up. Uh number one Eileen has in
the chat what if somebody is taking a
subperceptual dose and in that case this
is me speaking personally it may not be
something that could be said okay I have
peak intensity and resolution and such.
So again, this may be an optional area,
but somebody that's taking a
non-perceptual perceptual dose in a
session, this might be something that
can help with again when it comes to the
type of uh and I know that this was
brought up before was uh the actual type
of medicine, the intensity, the amount
of salosin/silocybin,
other things in it to kind of do a
little bit of research study on that as
well. Um so I'm going to let everybody
else kind of same thing. put your hand
up if you have any comments to add to
this. And we got one from Gregory.
>> Um, just a brief note. Um, and help me
understand if I'm in the right space
here, Dan, cuz this is like your your
ship that's driving. Uh if it's my
understanding that the
the lane for this conversation is
definitely we'll use the term
therapeutic dose or we can find another
word for that but this is like somebody
who's planned to take uh planned and
prepared to take a very specific dose
and this is the administration setting
and the context for this data set is a
psychoactive dose not a subperceptual
dose. I think the con the conversation
around um other like lower dose
applications um is kind of a later in
the program
down the road sort of conversation. Is
that correct?
>> Yeah, you you hit it on there. But this
was brought up uh of course on the
dosage committee uh to kind of say is
there a way that we could get some
tracking and some research on on on this
as you said through therapeutic dose.
Exactly.
And so again, that's why I made that
comment up there that some fields may be
optional. So therefore, this may not be
something that is entered in every
session just because of of that. Again,
as this goes through, the idea would be
there would be a best practice that
would say that if this then that uh is
what we would be hoping for. So um
yeah, James, I see James has his hand
up.
Hey Dan, question on just the prep time.
Um, let's say we met with the the
patient three times and each session was
an hour.
Are we looking for the person
individually filling this out to say
that total time I spent is 180 minutes.
Is that your kind of thought behind
this?
>> Yeah, my sessions.
>> You're exactly right. No, you're exactly
right, James. is that the idea being
this would be the accumulative time
before the actual uh administration of a
dose. So if that took place over time
that would all be collected so that we
would so in the research knows that this
would be as much time before the
administration and then there may be
additional administrations from other
sessions again there would be prep time
for those up until that next there's
integration later but that's exactly
right this would be preparation for an
administration
and did you have a follow-up question to
that because I just want because I
didn't want to just say yep that's the
answer we move on okay thanks
Yeah. Yeah. You bet.
>> Yeah. In response to that, I think if I
was analyzing data around this um
on if I was just looking at a data set,
I would want the
day of session like the prep time being
a patient entered the office until the
time that they were administrated a
dose. That to me that would be the prep
time. And then another category of
measure would be um number of
preparatory sessions, how long those
sessions are and how what you know we
just entered dates and times of
sessions. So I could see if someone uh
was doing preparatory sessions with a
talk therapist for 3 months in
preparation for the administration
meeting. And I think that those are very
different things that um
deserve separate measure.
And this would be okay. I see what
you're saying.
>> Does that make sense? Um does kind of in
response to what James was saying.
>> It does. I I just I'm also because that
would open the door to having other
conversations about what was I mean it
could be. I'm not saying it is. What was
discussed? What was this for? You know,
so it would kind of add to the data
collection, which is perfectly fine.
Again, it just means like we just go
back to, you know, because I just don't
want it to be honorous for the
facilitator. One, uh, and two, that we
actually have the reason to collect it.
Meaning that we would say like, oh, if
there were four sessions that were this
much time compared to one session that
was this much time, is there? So, I see
the difference between the two. I just
want to be able to be respectful of it
at the moment, but we can kind of I want
to kind of dig into that a little bit
more. So, thanks for bringing that one
up.
>> But I I would I would encourage
constraining the prep time on this form
to the day of administration as opposed
to like amalgamating hours
and then maybe a question like did this
person prepare a yes or no and then that
can that data can live elsewhere.
>> Got it. And actually that idea of saying
session prep. So when uh I answered
James on that one and said that would be
an accumulation of session prep time
that this probably makes more sense to
say that the session prep day of
administration. Um I'm going to let this
kind of discussion kind of continue on
with that. So want people to kind of
challenge me. Should this be the day of
administration? Should we then open up
if not completely other data fields that
say dates and times for other
administration prep before the
administration? Um and so I'm don't want
to get it too confusing at this point,
but I do want to continue that
conversation and stretch that out. So,
um I want to get other people's opinions
on this too or any other comments on it
and we'll try to reach some consensus.
So, next one. I know that uh Dan has his
hand up.
Um hi. Yeah. Um quick question. Um well
or comment uh for time of peak
intensity.
>> Yes.
>> Um that one's going to be a hard one to
judge from the facilitator and even from
the uh person taking the it especially
if they are firsttime person. So that's
going to be a hard um met matrix to uh
um be able to I guess pinpoint it. It is
I think it's a lot of subjectiveness as
well. I mean I do understand that um I
believe that it may be in and this is
again personal like I said this was also
recommendation from a different
committee. So uh this is something to
kind of work through again in the best
practice side. But on the personal side
I know that there are uh a a time period
where you can kind of gauge to say
within this time period this was my peak
time uh or this was kind of the
beginning. I could kind of feel kind of
the bell curve of effects and such.
Again, very subjective, but nonetheless,
still
still data to analyze when you're
talking about the therapeutic dose idea,
different types of uh psilocybin, etc.
So, uh that's that's why I think they
were interested in having something on
this to say like is is there at least
some way that we can collect some data
to them. So, I hope it it doesn't
perfectly explain everything. I know and
it's not the you know the absolute most
scientific when you say like oh there
are other tools that we might be able to
use to find that but this would be based
upon user experience and subjectiveness
from clinician and patient
and Lisa
um I have a question about integration
are you going to measure the number of
sessions um of integration sessions
later in this protocol or is it
something that should be included here?
>> No, you're exactly right. Integration is
outside of this administration of the uh
medicine session. So, there is another
table coming up in just a little bit
that we will look at on that. So,
absolutely.
And then uh we've got James.
Hey Dan, just my thought back on this uh
talk with the prep time. Um that was
kind of like where I was kind of going
earlier was is it from the time when
they kind of show up at the center or
with the facilitator
or is it the prior sessions and the
prior time spent even like Gregory said
even months out potentially for some
patients. Um, and I just I just want to
make sure we're just capturing it
correctly, but not overly burning some
like you said, you know, this data. But
it's I think it's something to keep
talking about here because it's
important that,
>> you know, when they come in, do we spend
an hour with them, you know, and that's
that's what we're trying to say or I
liked your idea too of accumulation, but
are we capturing everything in that that
we need to with prep? That's all
thoughts. Now, I think that's a very
valid point and so I'm really glad that
uh you know both you and Gregory and
everybody else has been kind of pushing
on this because it allows us to say for
this right now um I'm kind of changing
my thought on this to say that this is
probably this data is probably the best
one to say the time spent with the
patient in this session of
administration as you said like coming
in the door how much time was spent in
preparation before the administration of
the dose, not all the other potential
prior sessions before any administration
of dose so that we can kind of draw that
line of separation and then possibly add
other data elements, data fields or
however that might look so that we don't
just get too messy with the data. So I
really appreciate the push back on this
and so that's kind of where I'm staying
at this moment. We could say is during
this this session right now that I
walked in the door and I'm having the
administration of medicine. So, and then
we can kind of bring up that next one to
add more data into it. That's my
thoughts. I I like I said, push back on
it. Let me know what you think.
>> I know Lisa still has got her hand up,
so I want to make sure Lisa, if please
unmute and
>> I'm sorry, I accidentally forgot to put
it on.
>> No, no, no, no, no. That's fine. I
That's fine. I just want to make sure if
there was anything else to add.
Um, and so before we move on to the next
one, like I said, any other comments on
this? Uh, and again with with my
comments saying for the moment Oh, yes,
Danielle.
>> Hi. Yeah, I wonder I haven't uh gone
into all these slides in depth, but are
you allowing time for the facilitator to
do a revision of the assessments for
potential vulnerabilities?
Well, personally for this uh committee,
I don't know if that's necessarily our
place. I'm just saying that out of hand
uh to do so. So, I feel that that's
probably something that might be to be
brought up in other committees of like
uh I can't tell you which one it might
be, but Oh, Brenda, maybe helpful.
Rescue me.
All right. Um, so, um, this would
probably be in the clinician's notes,
um, because this is this is not really,
um, that measurable in in this in this,
um, meeting here. So, uh that could come
into the next meeting as far as how a
note will be written um what is um
coming up for the client and uh so on
and so forth.
>> Thank you. And I know that as sessions
go through and integration takes place
again just kind of what Danielle brought
up there could be other changes to
things as well. So it doesn't mean that
there wouldn't be any changes. It's just
for the data collection part. I'm not so
sure. But please, Danielle, I know your
mic's still open, so kind of speak back
on that, too.
>> Uh, yeah. No, I that might this might
not be the right place. I'm just looking
at prep time and thinking uh one would
hope that the prep time included reading
the notes um
>> and and and
sign, you know, just some kind of u
acknowledgement of having read it,
>> right? and through I know that a lot of
the best practices when it comes down to
the facilitation that's exactly right
would be the best practice for the
clinician is to review all prior history
notes things like that and then to have
conversations with pay I mean that's
definitely going to have to be part of
the actual session itself so you're
exactly right Gregory
>> yeah again just to bring this back into
the lane of focus um this is collecting
data on the patient's exper experience
rather than um and and I think
collecting data on clinician practice is
an insanely valuable um topic and I
think we should definitely look at doing
that like once we're once once we're in
motion like what clinical practices
should we track that have specific
efficacy or outcomes based on patient
data but I think um regarding the time
that a clinician spends reading the
notes prior to the session. Um I think
that sits outside of this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I that the idea uh to expand
this into something a little bit larger
also will you know as we go through and
especially as education training
facilitators you know that kind of start
coming on. That's exactly right because
it will come back especially as we start
looking at some of the next things of
challenging experiences and session
integration and such to say like what
kind of things can we collect? What are
we seeing? what gaps are we seeing out
there in sessions and so absolutely uh
so for this before we move on to the
next one same thing I would love to have
kind of a consensus to say at this
moment we're okay with some of the
things we've talked about on this and
we're good with moving forward
thank you all very much for that and you
can lower your hands we'll move on to
the next one which is the challenging
events reporting um challenging/adverse
events reporting. So just to bring this
up this would be from the administering
clinician. Um we had no changes from any
of our previous uh meetings that we've
had. So this just links back to the
session. Uh the event category would be
based upon is this a psychological,
physiologial, physiological or
behavioral. Um so was this a panic
attack? Was this hypertension for
example? a detailed narrative of what
the CE was, the severity uh and there is
CTCAE that is the guide that uh most
medical professionals utilize for
hundreds of hundreds of different types
of experiences from a scale from one to
five. Uh so that would be something that
could be utilized. So was this a very
mild event? Was this a tragic event? The
intervention, what intervention was
tried? um anything from verbal
deescalation, rescue meds or EMS
transport. Was there just any kind of
intervention provided that helped the
challenging event? Uh but again, this is
idea to say on what threshold will we
look at in the future to trigger any
kind of monitoring suicidality if there
was anything there utilizing uh the
Colombia scale uh and uh the duration of
the adverse or the challenging
experience there. So, was this just a
very brief encounter or was this a
persistent adverse effects? Uh, I know
that uh Gregory brought up in our last
meeting about uh serotonin syndrome and
so this could be a way that that could
be also addressed or reported or
captured in this as well. Um, and so
love to hear comments, thoughts, ideas
on this, any changes that we need to
make to these data elements. Uh,
I keep forgetting to lower my after
voting. We need a voting box.
>> Maybe we got the thumbs up somewhere up
there. Um, but yeah, let's let's kind of
open up. Is there's any changes?
Anything that you would like to see
before we kind of make any kind of
consensus decision on this is just data
elements. Again, this can expand over
time, but at least this is kind of a our
initial idea of data elements that we
could collect for C's.
I think any comments on that. Um, love
to hear if you could raise your hand to
say, "Yep, we're good with this is a
reportable area for C reporting."
That's okay. Okay, I only see three. So,
what I would love everybody to do is
kind of bring your hands down. Uh
because that's that's means that there's
more discussion to be had on this. So, I
would love to kind of let anybody bring
their discussion up as to um maybe why
if anything we need to change.
I'm not seeing any comments, but let me
try this again. Like, are we good with
moving forward from this slide? Um, and
if you can raise your hand then again I
just want to make sure I've just
captured everybody. I don't like to move
forward if I don't have a good good
consent. Okay, thank you. I appreciate
that. Uh, I like I said, if I don't get
a good number, I always think, okay,
there's a reason somebody's not saying
something. So, I appreciate you having
your hands up for that. Um, thank you.
And this kind of goes to, and I lost you
on the screen. I know you're out there
somewhere, but somebody had asked about
like um like the integration side of
this. And so I've kind of labeled this
clinical outcomes or follow-ups. This
would be the integration clinician.
Could be the exact same administering
clinician, but I just have this set as
integration clinician here. Um linking
back to the patient, the date of
integration followup. And this will
allow us to track like how many you know
what if this was multiple sessions
before another administration. Uh what
was the setting type was this at clinic
home was this virtual the modality. Uh
and this was brought up from our
previous committee was a kind of a free
text box about what were the therapeutic
approaches that was used in this
follow-up integration. Uh and then other
data that we could collect in this time
because of uh uh things that could be
brought up during this time. So, for
example, the MEQ uh the challenging
experience uh score and then there's
other types of numbers that could be
used to a depression score, PTSD score,
anxiety score, substance. Would this be
a way for us to track over time uh from
a baseline before treatment was started?
Have we made any effect changes in in
any of those numbers? Doesn't mean that
every one of them is filled out. It just
means depending upon the patient's
qualification and entered into the uh
program, what are we looking at? What
are we tracking? Um and so love to hear
thoughts, questions, concerns on on this
side.
Okay. Not seeing any. Uh can I get a
raise of hands for everybody that's okay
with this on the follow-up integration
uh data collection.
Perfect. Thank you all very much for
that.
And then the last one that we'll take a
look at and this is kind of what uh Dan
had brought up uh from the previous
comment there was this medicine uh kind
of table. Medicine table then would be
entered in through the licensed grower
side. Uh and this would be the uh
information that comes in from uh the
certificate of uh analysis and such. So
product lot number again that ties back
to the administration of the dosage. Uh
the psilocybin milligrams per gram,
salosin milligrams per gram and then and
these may change because I know that
there was some good discussion about
like MTP a uh APF and those kind of
things. So don't you know don't sling
any arrows at the moment. I know those
me those names might change but this is
kind of at least the calculation concept
that we had looked at at one point in
time. So this may change absolutely when
it comes down to that but I just wanted
to kind of bring this in as a way to
collect that data. Uh and so I'll kind
of let this now stay open. I'm going to
read a couple of things in the chat box
before I let the hands go in. um by
Cana. I'm in private practice out of
state as a nur nature nature I'm going
to horrible at pronouncing anything
today. Naturopathic doctor midwife. It
seems there are three or more potential
providers, diagnostic, referring
clinician, facilitator, and prep. Uh and
I'm just saying that because I don't
know along the flow at this moment if
this is all the same type of person or
not. So I've left it like that. Not to
say they're three different people. It's
just three different parts of the flow.
Eileen Brewer occurs to me that while
pain isn't specifically mentioned as a
condition that's going to be treated by
initial roll out end of life care and
pain care might be useful get before and
after pain assessments. Eileen if I
could ask you for a favor I love the
concept. Is there is there a a a scale
score type instrument that helps with
that? And if there is, would you be able
to drop that into the chat for me
please? And can oops prep integration
clinician all will need to have access
to others medical platforms and would
like to tremendous admin time pulling
reviewing records. Thinking of keeping
care financially accessible. Thank you.
Okay. And then we'll go to the hands
now. Gregory.
Um, I think if you want to simplify
this, um, you could just do, um, replace
all of the, um, MTP, AFP,
etc. with like, u chemists or like just
like bucket it into like whatever is
decided that we track or how we measure
the
disperate um, phenotypical expressions
of whatever medicine is administered. I
don't know. I I see I I'm just trying to
make this simpler for now as you as you
were suggesting.
>> Yeah. And uh so those last three are
calculated fields. So therefore based
upon the two fields above that would be
and I'm sure there's more things that
would go into the COA that would
probably be tracked into this. I just
don't know what they are yet until
everything kind of gets shaken out. So
um you're right, it could be simplified
by the time we're done based upon like I
said COA that comes in. I just want to
make sure that the clinician has all the
available data as they're bringing some
product up that they know exactly what
is there
and Dan.
>> All right. Yeah, Dan, Ros City Labs. Um
I
uh little history on the total uh
theoretical solosen. We originally
enacted that here in Oregon and um we
quickly realized it was not uh a good
measure um because most people don't
know what silosin is and everybody does
know what psilocybin is. Everybody
refers to it as psilocybin. You guys'
program is referred to as psilocybin
program. Um and uh it really needs to go
off of total equivalents psilocybin.
We're actually changing the laws here in
Oregon to reflect that. Uh we had a work
group here recently. I think Dominic was
a part of it. Um it really is key that
you keep it um in a way that everybody
knows and understands. The clinical
trials where that uh Oregon based their
program off of was off of psilocybin.
Um, so I really encourage uh New Mexico
to not make the same mistake as Colorado
did. Colorado said Salosen, but that was
again partially Oregon's fault by
recommending I sat on the uh boards with
um Colorado and they're having problems
in Colorado with total potential solosin
or equivalents solosin and they're
trying to get to total equivalents
psilocybin. That's my two cents. Sorry.
Have a good one.
Thank you. Any other comments? Because
again, this one will probably again may
change based upon recommendations that
come out of like the dosing committee
from propagation committee, those kind
of things. So, this one will definitely
change flex and flow. uh to Dan's point,
it could be something that is changed
from another committee to this. So this
is not the RACI committee making that
kind of recommendation. So just just
know that. But we'll have some kind of
information table for the medicine side
of things. Um and then in the comments
there I have an input recommendation for
clinical outcomes if we can go to that
briefly and then sky do so dosing is
left up to practitioners again that is
something that comes out of other
committees uh and so I won't be able to
speak to that so that would probably
come out of the uh dosing committee if
I'm not mistaken
uh dosage administration and clinical
practice would that would be that
committee. So Sky, I know that if you're
interested in that one, that is coming
up on March no March the 16th at 9 to
11. And so scroll up in the chat and
you'll be able to see that link.
Absolutely. Um and then so I'll come
I'll go back to that slide in just a
second. Perfect. Yeah, thanks guy. Come
to all that you possibly can provide
input on that. Um so like I said, the
medicine slide here, this one will
change. So, I'm not going to say, "Yep,
we're locking this one in stone." I just
wanted to kind of bring up that we will
have some kind of traceability from all
the way through back to the medicine.
Okay. So,
clinical outcomes,
there's clinical outcomes. And then
Greg, if you want to raise your hand,
we'll mute you as well.
Um, I just wanted to put it on record to
that I would
recommend including in here with the
other scores you're collecting
uh measure called EDI. The EDI is the
ego dissolution score. It quantifies the
depth of ego dissolution required. Um
um the it measures the ego dissolution.
It's a it's a form just like the MEQ30
or whatever.
>> But if we're trying to target
therapeutic effect based on dosage, this
will be something that can help us see
um what type of dosage and what type of
person responds based on the other
identifying elements that we're
collecting from them.
>> Great. Thanks. And if you do me a favor,
the just the same way that I leaned it,
if you could find like a link to that
actual uh assessment, that score, drop
it into the chat. I'll copy it. I'm
pasting it into my notes as we're kind
of going here, too. So, appreciate that.
>> Uh, okay, cool. Yeah, I'll publish a
website or something. I have a whole
paper written up about it.
>> Perfect. Yeah.
All right. So, that takes us to the end.
I really appreciate for for the the the
slides for coming to the data
collection. So appreciate everybody's
comments um and push back and everything
like that. That's exactly what I want
this to be is that this is not, you
know, Dan's data collection system. This
is all of us. So I wanted to facilitate
that kind of conversation. Again, it's
not the last time we'll have it, but it
will be the last time for a while that
we'll have it. As more information comes
from other committees and as we start
moving forward into the program and
absolutely as the program actually gets
implemented into next year and we start
getting data, there'll be changes and
this committee will be making those
recommendations for changes. Um I
definitely would make the the comment to
say that things might come through our
committee that go out to other
committees to have them kind of think
about that to add back into it. So it
won't just be this committee makes that
decision and that's the way it's going
to be. We work in concert with the other
uh subcommittees and then ultimately
with the board to coalesce all of that
together. But that's just kind of our
work that we've been established for
this point. Um and that leads me to our
next thing which is this is what I
brought up at our last committee meeting
was that we do have some work that still
needs to be done out there and these are
things that can be done in parallel
while other committees are working on
their things that this necessarily will
not um we won't have to wait for them to
have something done. And also we can do
this to help inform and pass back and
forth. So this is where I bring up my
role as a teacher for 28 years. Uh it's
time for homework assignments. So the
last one I said we're going to have
these assignments, but we had no actual
assignments of people to it. So this is
where I'm going to ask for some help on
this. There's a few things that I would
like to um make sure that we get in
movement. Uh, one is since we've talked
about challenging events, adverse
experiences, uh, we need to talk about
what that monitoring and reporting
recommendations would look like. Uh, and
so I would love if this is something
that you would be interested in, if you
have information on, if you have passion
for, this is something. And so we'll I'm
going to kind of list all of them and
then I'm going to ask like hey who who's
interested in doing some like offline
work so that when we come back to our
next committee that you're like hey this
is something that I found this is
something I want to brought up this is
what we want to talk about. So I would
like what this will be is like you will
be kind of leading in this discussion in
the next committee meeting for that
topic. Um the second one is emergency
preparedness and response
recommendations because we know that
there may be challenging events that
require emergency response and for
facilitators to be prepared for those
things. So what does that look like?
This also helps uh us in any kind of
training that might be necessary for uh
first responders um for law enforcement.
We know that this was something that was
brought up in a lot of early discussions
were these kind of concerns that uh
people in public had. So we want to make
sure that we're uh cognizant and
thinking through those things. And the
third one is patient and community
education recommendations. Um so we know
that our patients need to be very well
informed uh before going into any kind
of psilocybin uh treatment and therapy.
And so what does that look like? What
information should they have? Um, this
is something that again going back to
best practices, something that we could
help create and then uh share through
our state system when it comes to this.
And then community education is really
about that harm reduction side. We know
that the public is going to have strong
feelings one way or another. And so we
want to make sure that we have community
education uh ideas that we can bubble up
through this committee and that uh the
Department of Health can help work with
us on as well for this and the public
campaigns and such. These are kind of
three things that this committee is kind
of tasked with and I would love to have
some help on that. So I would love if we
could kind of like hit each one of
these. So I'm going to ask for the first
one, the second one, and the third one.
So I'll ask that and if for any of those
as I hit them, please raise your hand
and say, "Hey, I would really like to
help take a lead on that one." So the
first one, the outcome, challenging
experience, monitoring, reporting,
recommendations. Is there anybody that
would love to kind of take the lead on
bringing back to this committee some
information that we could share?
Okay, James, I'm gonna I'm gonna let you
unmute because I don't want to just say,
great, James recommended. So,
thanks, James. U go ahead and I think
your mic is unmuted.
Thanks, Dan. Yeah, I definitely can take
the lead on that. I don't mind heading
up. Anybody's interested, let me know.
It's right in my wheelhouse. Um, you
know, I have some stuff on HPPD, other
other effects. You know, just in
general, we want to make sure we label
this correctly. We don't call it, you
know, the wrong things, which that's
very important. So, I'd be more willing
to help out.
>> Thanks so much for that. Really
appreciate that. And so, uh, I'm going
to I'm listed down there. Next meeting
is TBD. So, don't worry. It's not going
to be like great next week you got to
come and you know so we're going to have
a little bit of time between it maybe
about a month I've put it at TBD because
I want to make sure other work groups
have time to do their work and we're not
stepping on anything that they're
working on because they're some of their
work is a little bit more critical to
get into the public comment time. So um
we will definitely get an announcement
out when our next uh RAI meeting will
be. So thanks James. Second one is
emergency preparedness and response
recommendations. Again, this is for
especially our first responder uh law
enforcement community. So, love anybody
that would be interested in um in in
that.
And I'm going to put a pen in that one.
I don't see anybody's hands raised, so
that's okay. It's not that. But it will
come back up again just now. Uh, and
then the third one, and I see Eileen
dropped into the chat for patient and
community education recommendations. I
have a lot of experience on patient
community education. I would love to
help with that. Cong Oh,
congratulations, Eileene, since you
dropped it in the chat before anybody
raised their hand. Absolutely. I'm going
to let you take the lead uh on that one,
Eileen. Uh, and I'm just kind of taking
my notes here as well. Um, for patient
community education.
Great. And uh, and like I said,
appreciate everybody kind of sharing
that. And if you're working together,
awesome. Appreciate it, too. The idea
being is that James and Eileen will
bring back to our next and I'm going to
spend lots of time at our next meeting
for both of them to be able to kind of
share u what they have found on that.
I'm going to try to be respectful
because I know not everybody can make
every single meeting. So James and I I
understand that if for some reason I put
something out there to say this is the
time that we're going to have the
meeting. If you're like, "Nope, I can't
make it." I will probably tell you it
will still be this time on a Friday at
9:00 a.m. That's my intentionality for
it. So, I'd be looking into the future,
probably about a month, but as soon as I
start to solidify it with the DO team,
then we'll let you know. But, um, we'll
put that out as an announcement. If for
some reason you're like, "That's it. I
can't even make that." you can share
with us uh through the uh psilocybin uh
medical psilocybin email anything that
you have and then I'm happy to actually
help present on that as well. So don't
worry if you can be here please if
you're not able to be here I just don't
want to be disrespectful of the time
that you worked on that so we will still
share uh great as long as next Friday.
No it will not be next Friday. I can
tell you that like I said it'll probably
be about four weeks or so out from
today. So, and I'm going to go back to
just in case like no pressure on
anybody, but I'm just saying that on the
emergency preparation preparedness and
response recommendations. Um, if there's
nobody that really wants to take the
lead on that, that's fine. But then, oh,
Michelle, thank you very much. I
appreciate it because I was going to say
if there's anybody that was interested
that knows somebody that might be the
best fit to that, then bring that back.
But thank you very much Michelle for
Michelle
Bending
and I cannot type on my computer right
now
for emergency preparedness.
I really appreciate that very much for
uh James, Eileen, and Michelle for
taking those three leads on that because
this is what I want to do. I wanted to
not be the person that like runs I mean
I'll run the meeting but I just wanted
to make sure that everybody's voice
comes into this. So I appreciate this.
This is how we get some really rich
texture to to all of these things. So,
thanks so much for that. Uh, and again,
all at this point, all I can say for the
three of y'all is just find good things
that are out there that may have been
beneficial ideas, anything that you can
bring back to the committee, and we'll
spend our next committee digging into
each of those three and having some good
conversations. So feel free if uh you
know other people that need to be at
this committee for those three topics,
bring them to the next one uh and
encourage them to join that. And so
we've gone through and this will be the
ad hoc report outs. So that's what we
just finished up. Uh like I said, next
meeting date will be determined. We'll
get that out to you through the
announcements uh that go out through the
Department of Health emails. So if
you've signed up, please do. I know
Dominic dropped into the chat. There's
the email there. the program website and
I know that um there might be and I'll
kind of leave that up. I'm I'm te teeing
you up, Dominic. Uh I know that there
probably is a slide that you have that
shows how people can sign up for the
announcements to come to their email. So
I'm just kind of giving you that topic
to kind of find. So I didn't want to
just drop it on you immediately. Uh and
so somebody will share that in a minute.
I'm going to stop my share. But the last
thing that we'll be doing here is to do
our kind of public comment time which
allows for anybody to kind of share
anything that you would like in a period
of 3 minutes. Uh and so if you didn't
get a chance to say anything or there's
something you really wanted to say
especially pertaining to RACI, please
do. Um I'm going to let you tee that up
with raising your hands if you're ready.
And now I'll kind of let Dominic share
anything about how to sign up for those
newsletters.
>> Thank you, Dan. Uh, and actually Jorge
just put it in the chat and uh, really
it's just going to the website that
we've posted before and then in the
upper right hand corner there's a little
area that says sign up for e-news and
once you click on that it takes you to a
little form and you can click on uh
there's many different topics you can
sign up for with the department of
health and you just click on those and
then we send emails out periodically. So
that's pretty much about it and
otherwise uh public comment time.
>> Appreciate that. And I do see in the
chat that uh that you brought up there,
here's the information about how to
share public comments. All the details,
all the information if anybody wanted to
share anything to be attached to this
meeting as well. So thank you. And yeah,
so public comment time. If anybody has
anything that they would like to share,
this is your time. Just raise your hand
and we'll get you unmuted so that you
can kind of share with the team.
Oh no, I've talked your ears off. Oh no,
nobody wanted to say anything. This is
your time. Please,
Kate, thank you very much. I'll read the
comments and if people are dropping into
the chat then, uh, so one that I saw up
a little bit higher, Sky, thank good
work, Dan. Thank you very much. Uh,
Kate, thanks again to everyone who was
contributing to the television,
respectful, and harmonious process. I
thank you. I really I really appreciate
everybody's contribution here today. Uh
D. Harvey King, thanks. Have a great
day, everyone. I like I said, this is
your time. I'm not going to end
anything, but I'm going to be able to
say I appreciate y'all being here today.
I know it's great Fridays, so I I'm glad
you're here. Don't forget Brenda's
meeting comes up at 1:00. Please sign up
for Brenda's meeting. If you still have
time today, and there's plenty of other
uh subcommittee meetings that you can
join in on. We would love to have you
come to those as well and share your
expertise and information. And that's
why we really appreciate your expertise
here. Uh, and Gregory, please.
Um, I'm happy to end early today, but if
we do have time, I'd love to hear um
comment from the program about data
governance, like
who is going to collect this data, who's
going to have access to it, what are the
frameworks that we're going to ingest
and export this information and utilize
it, and like how and what type of
entities
can
benefit from this information um once we
start to collect it.
>> Sure. Thanks for the question.
>> Want to collect it?
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. Thank Thanks, Greg. And it's a
great question and it's one that's not
fully resolved and a lot of it is going
to quite frankly depend upon uh how much
is deemed to really be you know the
private information for the patient and
for their treatment what they consent to
because of course any patient enrolling
in the program will be able to consent
to either keep their information private
or to release it for research purposes.
Um, and so, uh, quite frankly, it's
going to really depend a lot on what
some of the the the
items as they are collected, what
exactly will be collected, what will be
considered part of research versus part
of treatment, um, and then really kind
of moving forward from there. Now,
especially with regard to research, as
there's additional funds down the road,
hopefully um for research and research
grants, some of that may change and may
open up a little bit, but regardless,
it's going to come down to the consent.
And so, we need to make sure that the
patients are consenting and that they
understand what they're consenting to.
Um, so while this is a treatment program
and a medical program, it is not as such
a research program by itself. However,
that does not mean that people can't
consent for that. So, we are of course
very protective for our on our patients
behalf of their data and their
information. And we've done this for
many years with regard to medical
cannabis patients for example where
there is some data that is collected. Um
but that data is only released upon the
consent of the patients and so it would
be something similar. I I do see more
information being collected with regard
to this program because in many ways it
is um much more uh it's newer from a
research standpoint than cannabis is uh
or andor has been. But it will really
come down to that consent and what type
of research comes up. We do need to be
very cautious not to just collect data
for the sake of collecting data. And I
think Dan, you know, emphasized that
very well earlier on. Um, and so we need
to make sure we have that balance. And
where exactly that'll be, I don't know
yet. We need to sort of see and and uh
make sure. But in the meanwhile, um,
we'll be always we will be erring on the
side of caution and protecting the
patients. I hope that's helpful at this
point.
Yeah, I just kind I I think I'm more
looking at looking for information about
the framework. Um
it's like I think there's a
a strong
reaction from the room that wow that's a
lot of work for the clinician that's a
lot of things for the person to be
writing. Um, is the program
a department from the department of
health going to like be asking for paper
or is there or are they going to be
providing a software solution or is
there a market for like a tool to be
used that like can integrate with the
department of health?
>> Well, that that's also a great question
on it, Greg. uh a lot of it actually
comes down to this is a medical program.
So practitioners are required to keep a
fairly comprehensive medical note that
is not something that in and of itself
is not something the department is going
to be collecting. Um that is between the
patient and the provider. And so there
are many you know um various medical
record uh solutions online um you know
that are digital. Some practitioners
still prefer to do paper. That really is
going to be up to them because that's a
part of their patient provider um you
know relationship and how they choose to
actually do items. Now from the program
standpoint, what the program collects
that will all be online and will be
digital. Um but again some of what is
being discussed are things that would be
a part of the regular medical record the
regular notes that patients file not
necessarily something that the program
would collect or that you know patients
are even going to want the program to
have that's between them and their
practitioner where that line exactly is
going to be drawn again that's a part of
what some of these committees need to
make that determination and so I can't
answer where that line is yet because it
hasn't been determined. Um, but also
realize that from a department
standpoint, um, we've done paper before.
You don't even want to know what it's
like when you have, uh, for example, at
one point at the height of the medical
cannabis program prior to legalization,
we had 137,000
patients. Uh, the records alone for that
are uh, it's an astounding amount of
paper. um and um we are not going down
that route. We have converted over to
electronic only and it has reduced
costs. It reduces time. It reduces and
it does this not just for the department
but also for the patients and for the
providers and the practitioners. And so
we'll make sure that things that are
collected by the department are done
electronically not through paper. Um
however again a lot of what we're
discussing is also just regular parts of
medical records that the patients and
the providers specifically the providers
will need to keep.
I just want to bank off of that just
very briefly uh Dominic is that um
clinicians have to hold the the hip of
um ethics here and so that's all kept
private and I think all of the data that
that's going to be collected um will be
assigned a number to um you know that
particular patient. So there's no outing
of anyone. uh this is solely for the
purpose of research and that as
clinicians that are in the trenches
doing this work, we're used to it. We're
used to taking assessments. We're used
to writing notes. We're used to um
educating our clients on what to expect.
Uh whether this type of medicine is
going to be proper for them or not. Um
that is up to their physician. So,
they're going to have to have a workup
uh physical workup on that. And uh
usually um if um I'm for example, if I'm
preparing a client and saying, you know,
we've been doing talk therapy for a
while, you know, you may want to here's
referrals to psychiatrist to talk to
them about medication. So, it it's going
to be a team effort between um the
therapist, their physician, their
psychiatrist,
and um the biller. So, the biller
doesn't really see any of that
information either. So, all of that's
protected under HIPPA.
Dan, I see you.
>> Um, I it was a kind of a question. You
mentioned electronic instead of paper. I
totally that's the best way to go. But
have you guys determined how you guys
are going to be doing your uh tracking
of the for the manufacturers from like a
seed to sale quote unquote like the
cannabis industry?
>> Yeah, it will. It's not been determined
at this point yet, but it will be an
online solution or a digital solution I
should say.
Okay, because I know Oregon uh decided
not to go with metric and Oregon
developed their own. I know it was kind
of expensive, but you guys ask Oregon if
you can get a copy of it and maybe tweak
it a little bit yourself to use for you
guys.
>> Thank you, Dan.
>> I see no other um comments. Eileen did
drop in the chat. So, thank you for
leading such a great meeting and amazing
process. New Mexico rocks. Yes, it does.
And Sky appreciate all the work y'all
are doing. Look forward to amazing
amazing meetings. Thank you so much. And
um not seeing any other comments. So,
yes, Gregory said it's like don't mind
getting a little early. Um but I want to
make sure that everybody has their time
if they want to. And if you're uh good
with the rest of this time, then we'll
stick around for a little bit. But
otherwise, I appreciate everybody's time
this morning. I really appreciate your
time and thoughts and ideas and
concepts. Please make sure to keep an
eye out for our next meeting and hope to
see you again.
>> Thank you everyone.